

Albert Bonmassip Bové

Front-end developer

610281195 - abonmassip@gmail.com - abonmassip.dev - Github: abonmassip - LinkedIn: abonmassip

About me

After 9 years living abroad in Zurich and Los Angeles, I recently returned to Barcelona in search of new opportunities and challenges. As a front-end developer, I primarily focus on building sites with React and Next.js, and creating 3D web experiences using Three.js. With a <u>background in computer graphics</u>, I am also proficient in Adobe Photoshop, Blender and the entire 3D graphics pipeline.

Skills

Programming: JavaScript, ES6, HTML, CSS, React, Next.js, Three.js, WebGL, Git, Node, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Responsive web development.

Computer Graphics: Adobe Photoshop, Blender, 3D modeling, texturing, lighting and rendering. **Languages:** Catalan, Spanish, English, German (beginner).

Work experience

3D Generalist - Freelance

Los Angeles, USA (2021 - 2023)

I worked for various LA-based clients providing high detail architectural renders, mostly rental apartments and small businesses before construction. Complete 3D pipeline, including modeling, texturing, lighting and rendering.

3D Generalist - Multiwebdia Global Creativity

Zurich, Switzerland + Los Angeles, USA (2017 - 2020)

Creation of logos, animations and media content for the European Final Four. Complete 3D pipeline, including modeling, texturing, lighting, animating and rendering.

3D Generalist - Soler&Palau

Zurich, Switzerland (2015 - 2016)

Production of Architectural Visualization renders to show ventilation system installations for domestic, commercial and industrial environments.

3D/2D Artist - EXON GROUP

Barcelona, Spain (2014 - 2015)

Creation of 3D environments, game-engine assets and interface elements for arcade machine games. My tasks involved modeling, image editing, texturing and animation.

Guitar Teacher - 5Passes

Sabadell, Spain (2012-2014)

Web designer and developer - Vallès School of Architecture ETSAV

Sant Cugat, Spain (2010-2011)

Web design using HTML/CSS, interactive content with Flash, poster design and video editing.

3D Modeler and animator - UPRA

Barcelona, Spain (2009)

Creation of 3D models and animations, integration of 3D elements into real-world footage, video and image editing, 2D animation.

Education

Bachelor's Degree in Multimedia Studies - Polytechnic University of Catalonia

Barcelona, Spain (2007 - 2011)

Continuing studies

Node.js Express MongoDB Bootcamp - Udemy

Next.js course - Fireship.io

Three.js Journey - Bruno Simon

Complete React Developer - *Udemy*

JavaScript30, Beginner JavaScript, ES6 for Everyone - Wes Bos

The Complete Web Developer - *Udemy*